7labs.io 2019-05-05

# Privacy Policy - 7labs

At 7labs.io (“Website”), the privacy of our visitors is of extreme importance to us. This privacy policy document outlines the types of information that is collected and recorded by 7labs and how it is used.

7labs (“us”, “we” or “our”) is the controller of your personal data provided to, or collected by or for, or processed in connection with usage of our website.

As a Visitor or Member of our Services, the collection, use, and sharing of your personal data are subject to this Privacy Policy (which includes our Cookie Policy and other documents referenced in this Privacy Policy).

## Data We Collect

### 1\. Data You Provide to Us

Personal Information is any information that can be used to individually identify you from a larger group. 7labs does not collect any Personal Information in order to provide services to users.

However, you may provide us Personal Information when you:

  * Contact us via Email
  * Register for an event
  * Subscribe to our newsletter
  * Request special services

The information that you provide in each case will vary. Depending on the situation, we may request your consent to use the Personal Information, along with the purpose of use, through relevant channels.

### 2\. Automated Information Collection

In addition to the information that you provide to us, we may also collect information about you during your visit to the Website. We collect this information using automated tools that are detailed below.

#### Log Files

7labs follows a standard procedure of using log files. These files log visitors when they visit websites. All hosting companies do this and a part of hosting services’ analytics. The information collected by log files includes internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, Internet Service Provider (ISP), date and time stamp, referring/exit pages, and possibly the number of clicks. These are not linked to any information that is personally identifiable. The purpose of the information is for analyzing trends, administering the site, tracking users’ movement on the website, and gathering demographic information.

#### Cookies & Web Beacons

A “cookie” is a small data file transmitted from a website to your computer’s hard drive. Cookies are usually defined in one of two ways, and we may use both of them: (1) session cookies, which do not stay on your computer after you close your browser, and (2) persistent cookies, which remain on your computer until you delete them or they expire.

These cookies are used to store information including visitors’ preferences, and the pages on the website that the visitor accessed or visited. The information is used to optimize the users’ experience by customizing our web page content based on visitors’ browser type and/or other information.

We use the following categories of cookies on our Website.

 **Functional:** These cookies are essential in order to enable you to move around the Website, use its features, show the cookie notification bar, remember your cookie acceptance choice and apply this choice. These cookies cannot track your browsing activity on other websites.

 **Analytical:** These cookies are placed to make it possible for us to analyze user interactions with this Website (with Google Analytics) and optimize it to serve better content and usability.

 **Social Media:** Our Website uses cookies from third-party social networking sites like Facebook, Twitter, etc., to improve the overall experience.

 **Advertising:** These cookies are placed in order to show you personalized advertisements (via Google AdSense) that are close to your interests. They are also used to limit the number of times you see an advertisement as well as help measure the effectiveness of an advertising campaign.

 **Third-Party Ad Networks and Services**  
Third-party ad servers or ad networks may use technologies like cookies, JavaScript, or Web Beacons used in their respective advertisements and links appearing on 7labs, which are sent directly to users’ browser. They automatically receive your IP address when this occurs. These technologies are used to measure the effectiveness of their advertising campaigns and/or to personalize the advertising content that you see on websites that you visit.

 **Google DoubleClick DART Cookie**

Google is one of the third-party vendors on our Website. It also uses cookies, known as DART cookies, to serve ads to our Website visitors based upon their visit to other websites on the internet. However, visitors may choose to decline the use of DART cookies by visiting the Google ad and content network Privacy Policy at the following URL – <https://policies.google.com/technologies/ads>

Note that 7labs has no access to or control over these cookies that are used by third-party advertisers. Our Privacy Policy does not apply to other advertisers or websites. Thus, we are advising you to consult the respective Privacy Policies of these third-party ad servers for more detailed information. It may include their practices and instructions about how to opt-out of certain options. You may find a complete list of these Privacy Policies and their links here: <https://7labs.io/ad-technology-providers>.

#### How can you control your cookies

If you do not wish to have cookies on your devices, you may turn them off at any time by modifying your internet browser’s settings. However, by disabling cookies on your device, you may be prohibited from full use of the Websites’ features or lose access to some functionality. We also offer you the ability to manage the types of cookies stored on your devices.

You can also opt out of having your anonymous browsing activity and ad preferences within various websites previously recorded by Analytical and Advertising cookies.

Google Analytics: <http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout>  
Google AdSense: <http://www.google.com/ads/preferences/html/opt-out.html>

#### Embedded Web Links

Links provided in our emails and, in some cases, on third party websites may include tracking technology embedded in the link. The tracking is accomplished through a redirection system. The redirection system allows us to understand how the link is being used by email recipients. Some of these links will enable us to identify that you have personally clicked on the link and this may be attached to the Personal Information that we hold about you. This data is used to improve our service to you and to help us understand the performance of our campaigns.

#### Embedded content from other websites

Articles on this Website may include embedded content (e.g. videos, images, articles, etc.). Embedded content from other websites behaves in the exact same way as if the visitor has visited the other website (Third-party partners).

These websites may collect data about you, use cookies, embed additional third-party tracking, and monitor your interaction with that embedded content, including tracking your interaction with the embedded content if you have an account and are logged in to that website.

#### Media

If you upload images to the website, you should avoid uploading images with embedded location data (EXIF GPS) included. Visitors to the website can download and extract any location data from images on the website.

## Who do we share your data with

7labs does not collect and store Personal Information in order to share them later with third-party partners or services. However, some of our third-party partners may collect your data when you interact with our Website. These partners include but not limited to:

Google – Website Analytics and Advertising [<https://policies.google.com/technologies/partner-sites>]  
Disqus – Commenting on articles published on our Website [<https://help.disqus.com/terms-and-policies/disqus-privacy-policy>]  
Facebook – Providing the ability to “Like” our official Facebook page from our Website [<https://www.facebook.com/policy.php>]  
List of Ad Technology Providers [<https://7labs.io/ad-technology-providers>]

## How long we retain your data

Personal Data can be stored up to 390 days. You can modify your [advertising personalization settings](https://adssettings.google.com/ "Google Ad Settings") with Google. If you would like to have your data removed, you may contact also our individual third-party partners.

## What we do with your data

We use your collected information for the following purposes:

  * To provide and maintain the Service
  * To provide analysis or valuable information so that we can improve the Service
  * To monitor the usage of the Service
  * To detect, prevent and address technical issues

## Transfer of data

Your information, including Personal Data, may be transferred to — and maintained on — computers located outside of your state, province, country or other governmental jurisdiction where the data protection laws may differ than those from your jurisdiction.

By agreeing to this Privacy Policy, using this website, and providing your personal data, you consent to this transfer of data. 7labs will take all steps reasonably necessary in order to ensure that your data is treated securely and in accordance with this Privacy Policy and no transfer of your Personal Data to an organization or a country will take place unless there are adequate controls in place including the security of your data and other personal information.

## Security of data

The security of your data is important to us. However, it should be borne in mind that no method of transmission over the Internet, or of electronic storage, is 100% secure. While we strive to use commercially acceptable means to protect your Personal Data, we cannot guarantee its absolute security.

## External Links

Our Service may contain links to other sites that are not operated by us. If you click on such a third-party link, you will be directed to that third-party’s site, which are governed by their own Privacy Policy. We strongly advise you to review the Privacy Policy of every site you visit.

We have no control over and assume no responsibility for the content, privacy policies or practices of any third-party sites or services.

## Children’s Information

Another part of our priority is adding protection for children while using the internet. We encourage parents and guardians to observe, participate in, and/or monitor and guide their online activity.

7labs does not knowingly collect any Personal Information from children under the age of 13. If you think that your child provided this kind of information on our Website, we strongly encourage you to contact us immediately and we will do our best efforts to promptly remove such information from our records.

## Scope of Policy

Our Privacy Policy applies only to our online activities and is valid for visitors to our website with regards to the information that they shared and/or collect in 7labs. This policy is not applicable to any information collected offline or via channels other than this website.

## Changes to Our Policy

7labs has the discretion to update this privacy policy at any time. When we do, we will revise the updated date at the bottom of this page. We encourage Users to frequently check this page for any changes to stay informed about how we are helping to protect the personal information we collect. You acknowledge and agree that it is your responsibility to review this privacy policy periodically and become aware of modifications.

## Consent

By using our website, you hereby consent to our Privacy Policy and agree to its terms, as well as our Cookie Policy.

If you are a resident of the European Economic Area (EEA), we will provide you a consent request that you can accept by clicking an opt-in button.

## Contact Us

If you have additional questions or require more information about our Privacy Policy, do not hesitate to contact us through email at  _0b111[at]7labsofficial.com_.

    This document was last updated on January 8, 2019
